[ Narrator ] Legend has it that it was written by the Dark Ones .
" Necronomicon Ex Mortes . "
Roughly translated : " Book of the Dead . "
The book served as a passageway to the evil worlds beyond .
( Screaming , screeching )
It was written long ago ...
( Cackling )
... when the seas ran red with blood .
It was this blood that was used to ink the book .
In the year 1300 AD ,
the book disappeared .
So what 's this place like ?
Well , it 's a little rundown , but , uh , it 's right up in the mountains .
- Are you sure it 's converted ? - Oh , yeah .
I think so .
( Chuckles )
- Oh ! - ( Chuckles )
Ow !
[ Ash ] So what do you think , kid ?
I love it , Ash .
I feel funny about being here .
What if the people who own this place come home ?
They 're not gonna come back .
Even if they do , we 'll tell them the car broke down or something .
With your car , they 'd believe it .
Hey . What do you say we have some champagne , eh , baby , huh ?
Sure .
After all , I 'm a man and you 're a woman .
At least , the last time I checked .
- Ok . - â  ª Bom-bom , bom-bom ... â  ª
Ugh !
Ah !
( Sings )
Hey ! There 's a ... there 's a tape recorder here .
See what 's on it .
[ Man ] This is Professor Raymond Knowby , Department of Ancient History ,
log entry number two .
I believe I have made a significant find in the castle of Kanda ,
having journeyed there with my wife Henrietta ,
my daughter Annie , and associate professor Ed Gatly .
It was in the rear chamber of the castle
that we stumbled upon something remarkable .
Naturum de Monte .
" The Book of the Dead . "
My wife and I brought the book to this cabin
where I could study it undisturbed .
It was here that I began the translations .
The book speaks of a spiritual presence .
A thing of evil that roams the forests and the dark powers of man 's domain .
It is through the recitation of the book 's passages
that this dark spirit is given licence to possess the living .
Recorded here are the phonetic pronunciations of those passages .
Kanda .
Estrata . Amantos ...
Ear-grets , gat .
Nos Feratos .
Kanda .
Amantos . Kanda ...
( Screams )
Linda ?
Hey , Lin ...
( Screaming )
( Cackling )
( Cackles )
( Gasps )
( Screams )
Linda .
( Thunderclaps )
( Deep growling )
( Screams )
( Growls )
It 's gone .
The sun 's driven it away .
Yeah .
For now .
Gotta ... Gotta pull out of here before nightfall .
( Voices echoing )
( Deep voice ) ' Join us ! '
( Shrieks )
Oh !
Oh ! Oh , my God !
No . No !
Oh , no .
No ! No !
I gotta ... I gotta get a grip of myself here .
( Tyres screeching )
( Groans )
( Roaring )
( Heavy breathing )
Thank you .
- Annie ! - Hi !
Mm . How did the expedition go ?
Great . I found the pages of the " Book of the Dead " .
Yeah . I got your telegram , thanks .
- So what condition are they in ? - Take a look .
- They haven 't aged a day in 3,000 years . - Maybe longer .
- When do we begin the translations ? - Tonight . All set with my father ?
It should be . I haven 't spoken with him in a week .
There 's no phone in the cabin .
I 'll take my car . It 'll take us an hour to get there .
Annie , you hinted that your father was on to something with his translations .
What has he found in the " Book of the Dead " ?
Probably nothing .
But just possibly the doorway to another world .
( Wind howling )
( Groans )
( Door creaks )
( Piano playing )
( Sobs )
( Gasps )
( Laughing )
Ah . ( Laughs )
Ah !
( Screams )
Dance with me !
Yeah , just ...
( Screams )
Ah , ah .
Hello , lover .
( Screams )
( Cackles )
( Groans , cackles )
- ( Screams ) - ( Cackles )
( Screams )
Work shed .
( Linda cackling )
Come on ! No !
( Screams )
( Grunts )
Even now , we have your darling Linda 's soul .
She suffers in torment .
You 're going down .
Chainsaw .
( Screams )
( Chainsaw stops )
( Chainsaw starts )
Please , Ash . Please don 't hurt me .
You swore ... you swore that we 'd always be together .
I love you .
No !
Yes ! Your love was a lie .
And now she burns in hell !
[ Ash ] Oh , yeah ? All right . OK .
( Groans )
( Sighs )
( Creaking )
( Voices echoing )
( Chair creaking )
( Gun cocks )
( Voices echoing )
( Creaks )
I 'm fine .
I don 't think so .
We just cut up our girlfriend with a chainsaw .
Does that sound fine ?
( Chuckling )
( Gasps )
( Screams )
You bastards !
You dirty bastards !
( Whimpers )
Give me back my hand .
Give me back my hand !
( Sobs )
Mm-hm .
Excuse me .
Is this the road to the Knowby cabin ?
That 's right . And you ain 't going there .
And why not ?
There must be another way in . There 's gotta be a road or something .
Sure ain 't no road .
Why the hell do you wanna go up there for , anyway ?
Huh ?
None of your business .
Hey . I just remembered . Why , yeah , that 's right .
There is a trail . Well , you could , uh ... follow Bobby Joe and me .
Sounds all right to me .
- But it 'll cost you . - How much ?
Forty-f ...
100 bucks .
Tell you what , you take my bags and you got a deal .
Sure !
( Chuckles )
( Voices echoing )
( Mutters )
No !
( Voices muttering )
( Voice muttering )
( Screams )
That 's right . So who 's laughing now ?
Who 's laughing now ?
( Screams )
Jesus Christ !
I thought she was talking about them two goddamn little bags .
( Grunts )
( Squealing )
Here 's your new home .
( Muffled voices echoing )
( Clattering )
( Voice squealing )
( Squealing )
( Sighs )
( Voice singing )
( Squealing )
( Laughs )
You son of a ...
( Grunts )
( Voice muttering )
( Squealing )
Gotcha , didn 't I , you little sucker ?
A double-barrel here . I 'll blow your butts to kingdom come !
See if we don 't .
- ( Creaking ) - Huh ?
( Laughs raucously )
( Raucous laughter )
( Cackles )
Oh !
( Laughter )
( Cackles )
( Squeaking )
( Laughs )
( Yells )
( Knocking )
( Screaming )
( Door creaking )
( Shouts )
( Groans )
- Hit him ! - Ah !
You little dirty bastard .
- You gonna be all right , honey ? - I don 't know . I think so .
You just sit still for a minute .
You know this son of a bitch ?
[ Ed ] No . We thought our father was gonna be here .
Oh , my God . Where are my parents ?
( Gasps )
What the hell did you do to them ?
What the hell did you do ?
Annie , come here ! Annie !
Come here ! Come here .
We 'll throw him in there .
Crazy buck 's gone blood simple .
I ...
I ... I made a mistake .
- Wait , wait , wait . - [ Ed ] Bring him over here .
[ Ash ] No ! I made a mistake .
Damn right , you black-mouth son of a bitch !
I hope you rot down there !
- Oh , shit ! - I know it hurts , baby .
But everything 's gonna be fine .
In about five minutes , I 'm gonna go fetch the sheriff and bring him ...
I checked all the rooms .
Your folks aren 't here . Maybe they never came .
But these are my father 's things .
[ Raymond ] It 's only been a few hours since I 've translated and spoken aloud
the first of the demon resurrection passages ,
from the " Book of the Dead " .
Shh . Listen up . This is my father 's voice .
And now I fear that my wife has become host
to a Kandarian demon .
May God forgive me for what I have unleashed unto this Earth .
Last night , Henrietta tried to
kill me .
How ?
It 's now October 1st , 4 : 33pm .
Henrietta is dead .
I could not bring myself to dismember her corpse .
But I dragged her down the steps and I buried her .
I buried her in the cellar .
God help me , I buried her in the earthen floor of the fruit cellar .
( Screams )
- What the hell was that ? - Somebody 's down there with him .
- No . It can 't be . - Let 's get the fuck outta here .
Someone 's in my fruit cellar !
( Screams )
Someone with a fresh soul .
Let me out ! There 's something down here !
- Let him out . - It 's a trick .
- Let him out ! - Move it !
Open those chains up .
Come to me .
Help ! Help me !
[ Henrietta ] Come to sweet Henrietta .
- There 's something down here ! - ( Chuckles )
( Cackles )
- Help me ! - [ Annie ] Hurry !
Help me , please !
I 'll swallow your soul !
( Screams )
( Screaming )
Help me !
[ Annie ] Do something !
( Screaming )
( Screams )
( Squealing )
( Grunts )
There 's something out there .
That ...
That witch in the cellar is only part of it .
It lives
out in those woods .
In the dark .
Something ...
Something that 's come back from the dead .
Jake ! Please , let 's get the hell out of here !
- We 're going , baby . - Nobody goes out of that door !
- Not till daylight ! - Listen to me .
[ Henrietta ] â  ª Hush , little baby Don 't say a word â  ª
â  ª Momma 's gonna buy you a mockingbird â  ª
â  ª If that mockingbird don 't sing â  ª
â  ª Momma 's gonna buy you a diamond ring â  ª
â  ª If that diamond ring turns brass â  ª
â  ª Momma 's gonna buy you a looking glass â  ª
Remember that song , Annie ?
I used to sing it to you when you were a baby .
Mother ?
Unlock these chains . Quickly .
No .
You were born September 2nd , 1962 .
I remember it well because it was snowing .
So strange it would be snowing in September .
That thing in the cellar is not my mother !
( Screaming )
We are the things that were and shall be again .
( Ed cackles )
Spirits of the Book . We want what is yours . Life .
( Cackles )
- Dead by dawn . - [ Henrietta ] Dead by dawn .
Dead by dawn ! Dead by dawn !
( Echoing voices ) Dead by dawn .
( Screams )
- Let me out ! - [ Jake ] You son of a bitch .
( Growls )
No !
Where are you going ? Help us , you fucking coward !
Quickly ! Set me free .
( Shouts )
( Screams )
[ Ed ] We live ! We live still !
( Groaning )
( Wind howling )
That 's funny .
What ?
That trail we came in here on ?
Well , it just ain 't there no more .
Like ...
Like the witches swallowed her up .
It 's so quiet .
( Growling )
( Clock ticking fast )
( Screams )
( Banging )
( Gunshots reverberate )
( Horses ' hooves clopping )
( Growling )
( Creaking )
What the hell was that ?
Maybe something trying to force its way into our world .
( Screeching )
( Explosions )
( Door creaks )
It 's in there .
We 'll all go in together .
Hell , no ! You 're the curious one .
Hey .
I 'll go with you .
( Door creaks )
( Banging )
Shit .
I told you there weren 't nothing in here , no how .
( Rattling )
( Glass smashing )
( All scream )
Holy mother of mercy .
- [ Annie ] Father ? - Annie ?
There is a ... dark spirit here
that wants to destroy you .
Your salvation lies there .
In the pages of the Book .
Recite the passages . Dispel the evil .
Save my soul .
And your own lives !
Jake ... you 're holding my hand too tight .
Baby , I ain 't holding your hand .
( Screams )
Hey ...
Where 's Bobby Joe ?
( Screams )
( Flies buzzing )
Stop !
( Screams )
Hey . Where the hell is she ?
We gotta go out there and find her .
If she went out in those woods , you can forget about her .
- ( Gasps ) - What 's wrong ?
It felt like someone just walked over my grave .
What 's that picture ? What is that ?
[ Annie ] In 1300 AD ,
they called this man the Hero from the Sky .
He was prophesied to have destroyed the evil .
He didn 't do a very good job .
Can you find it ?
Here it is . Two passages .
Recitation of this first passage
will make this dark spirit manifest itself in the flesh .
Why the hell would we wanna do that ?
Recitation of the second passage
creates a kind of ... rift in time and space .
And the physical manifestation of this dark spirit
can be forced back into the rift .
- That 's the best translation I can ... - ( Gun cocks )
Uh-huh . That 's right .
I 'm running the show now .
We 're gonna go up there in them woods and look for Bobby Joe .
Once we find her , we 're getting the hell out of here !
No , you idiot !
It will kill us all .
She 's dead by now . Don 't you understand ?
With these pages , at least we have a chance .
( Gasps )
Bunch of mumbo-jumbo bullshit !
These pages don 't mean squat !
Besides , now you ain 't got no choice .
Now move !
- Move . - You 're nuts .
- I said move ! - Oh , you stupid fool !
I 'll blow your fucking head off !
( Creaking )
( Groaning )
Hey .
No trail .
Where to now ?
Uh , uh ...
Bobby Joe !
( Growling )
You 'll get us all killed !
- Leave him alone ! - Get outta here !
Bobby Joe !
Bobby ... Joe !
Bobby Joe ... where are you , girl ?
( Creaking )
( Screaming )
( Screams )
You 're nuts !
Annie !
- ( Clattering ) - ( Gasps )
( Creaking , rattling )
( Banging )
- ( Screams ) - ( Grunts )
No .
Aargh ! No , no !
( Groans )
( Screams )
- ( Groans ) - I 'm sorry .
Get me in the other room .
Get the axe . We 'll kill him when he comes back .
But first , pull this damn thing out of me !
( Screams )
( Jake groans , coughs )
I can 't breathe . I can 't breathe .
Hurry ! Hurry !
I 'm trying . I 'm trying !
- ( Screams ) - Shut up !
Shut up ! Shut up !
Check out ... beside the windows .
- Check the windows . He 's probably ... - ( Screams )
Help me !
( Screaming )
Oh , God !
( Screams )
( Growls , chuckles )
( Groans )
( Screams )
- No , no ! Wait ! - ( Screams )
Listen to me !
I 'm all right now .
That thing is gone .
( Annie grunts )
Damn it ! I said I was all right !
Are you listening to me ? Do you hear what I 'm saying ?
I 'm all right !
I 'm all right .
OK , maybe you are .
But for how long ?
If we 're gonna beat this thing , we need those pages .
Then let 's head down into that cellar and carve ourselves a witch .
( Cackles )
( Squeaks )
Groovy .
( Creaking )
Those pages are down there somewhere .
( Voice echoes )
( Screams )
( Groaning )
The pages . Quick !
( Screams )
( Henrietta cackles )
Nos Feratos , Kalamimnon , Kanda !
( Gasps )
( Screams )
( Henrietta cackles )
[ Annie ] No !
( Whistles )
( Screams )
- Let 's go . - ( Screams )
( Cackles )
( Groans )
( Squeals )
Swallow your soul . I 'll swallow your soul .
( Screeches )
â  ª Hush , little baby , don 't say a word â  ª
â  ª Momma 's gonna buy you a ... â  ª
â  ª Mockingbird â  ª
( Screeches )
( Groans )
Hey , I 'll swallow your soul !
I 'll swallow your soul ! I 'll swallow your ... ( Groans )
- ( Gun cocks ) - Swallow this .
( Sobs )
( Annie screams )
I only completed the first of the passages .
That was to make the evil 3 thing of the flesh .
You didn 't finish it ?
There 's still the second passage . The one ...
The one to open the rift and send the evil back .
Well , start reciting it ! Now !
( Screams )
( Growls )
Don 't look , Annie ! Finish the passages !
Get rid of it !
Kanda ! Amantos ! Kanda !
Kanda ! Somonda Reba Neda Gyes !
Enzeen !
( Grunts )
( Groans )
No !
Nos Feratos !
Amenal !
Akadiv !
( Yells )
Idres .
( Screams )
( Groans )
[ Woman ] ' We 've won ! ' [ Man ] ' We 've won ! '
Victory is ours !
( Chainsaw whirs )
( Screams )
Kanda .
You did it , kid .
By God ...
( Groans )
( Screams )
For God 's sake ! How do you stop it ?
( Explosions )
( â  ª Classical violin playing â  ª )
( Groans )
Slay the beast ! ' Tis a deadite !
- Huh ? - ( Screeching )
Run ! Run for the castle !
( Screeches )
Hail he who has come from the skies
to deliver us from the terrors of the deadites !
( All ) Hail !
Hail !
No ...
- ( Warriors ) Hail ! Hail ! - No !
- No ! - Hail ! Hail !
No !
Hail ! Hail !
No ! No !
No !